Laios and crew are returning to the surface.
I just don't want to lose any of you.
Me neither.
While their bonds are growing ever stronger,
let's go back in time a bit.
You're finally conscious.
Are you feeling all right?
Your injuries weren't too severe.
I had to use goat's blood to replace what you lost.
It'll do for now, but you should return to town soon.
It's good you weren't still in the water,
or you'd have been fish food.
You should be thankful to whoever pulled you out.
Are you thinking what I am?
Kuro!
I know this scent.
Elf. Tall man. Half foot. Dwarf.
The ones who stole our treasure.
I had a feeling it was those guys!
The revival fee, please.
Enough for the goat's blood is fine.
That's right.
We were...
Assaulted by some fishmen.
I guess we must have died again.
This is plenty, thank you.
They're adventurers?
Aren't you...
Need something?
No.
Let's go, Nomari.
Right!
Got a soft spot for dwarves?
Hm?
You have no integrity.
Hey, I don't use someone's height to determine whether or not I hang out with them.
That's so.
Our food is gone!
It got stolen by those guys again!
Food.
Are you kidding me?!
It's so weird.
They always take all our food, but none of our money.
Maybe they keep running out of it?
So annoying.
We really should teach them a lesson.
What's the plan, Kabru?
Hmm.
There's no choice.
Let's go back.
Wait!
You're joking, right?
Shouldn't we go after them?
We don't have any food, though.
So we shouldn't go any further.
How about we admit defeat for now?
Like that guy said before he left, we have to be thankful that we're alive at all.
If that's what you want to do, I guess I'll stick with you.
I will, too.
If you promise you won't give up on finding those filthy criminals, then I'm fine to return.
I promise, Ren. Thanks.
Koro will do what Mikbel does.
Oh, man.
I can't believe we're not making any profit this time.
There's so much fog.
Hey, be careful, everyone!
This fog didn't occur naturally.
It's from a monster.
A fish man?
There are so many of them.
I guess there's no choice.
Come on!
The way it uses that axe seems familiar.
This swinging motion.
I know it all too well.
That's right.
This is...
Shh.
Everything's fine.
Just calm down.
Daya.
It's me.
This fog's illusion magic.
The confused one with their weapon drawn is Koro.
And the one zoning out across from him is home.
He has a habit of freezing up when things get a bit crazy.
The one who ran off is probably Mik.
So, the one that poses the most dangerous...
Ren.
She's already in mid-chant.
She has the power to turn us all into ashes instantly.
The only peaceful way to stop a chanting magic user is...
Ren.
You get it, right?
This is all an illusion.
It's too bad she looks like a monster.
Now then.
In order to stop this fog that was conjured...
Huh.
This isn't the right one.
Those who attack with weapons aren't casters.
They're always observing things from afar.
That one.
All right, all right.
We surrender.
So would you mind letting go of my mage friend?
Wait a minute.
They're the corpse retrievers from upstairs.
I don't think this reunion is just a coincidence.
You guys followed us, right?
What do you mean?
It's more profitable to retrieve corpses from a deeper floor,
because the island pays more for it.
We were angry about our stuff being stolen.
And while we were trying to get back,
we went to a floor that was above our skill level.
So all they had to do was follow us,
and they would find more profitable corpses.
Oh, so annoying.
But you were a little too late.
When you found us,
we'd already been revived by someone else,
and we were heading back to the surface.
It made you panic.
So you decided to use illusion magic
to turn us all against each other.
You're a little off base.
What we wanted was for you to catch up to the thieves.
Having you kill each other would have been the best scenario.
But it's really a shame.
We didn't think you'd die so quickly
from being attacked by mere monsters.
You're a little...
Infighting and stealing between adventurers is a crime.
I'm reporting you to the island lord.
How about we make a deal?
It'd be wasteful for you to go back empty-handed.
Two of my party members were unfortunately taken out.
Deliver them to the resurrection office.
You should earn a decent amount of money for doing that.
Those two were just unconscious.
We'll testify that they got attacked by fishmen.
As for splitting the reward,
we're gonna take 40.
No, 30% of it.
How's that?
It's a pretty good deal, isn't it?
All right.
I'll do it.
Kabru.
Oh, damn you.
Yeah, that makes more sense.
I'm glad you did the right thing.
Humanoids are so easy to deal with.
Every single dwarf, gnome, and tallman,
they all tend to have identical weak points.
They move their bodies in the same way, too.
It's too bad monsters aren't like that.
Kuro, go find Mika, bring him back, will ya?
Kuro!
Kabru.
Hmm?
What about him?
Please let me go, I swear to you!
I didn't know about any of this!
You don't aim to lift the dungeon's curse,
nor eradicate the monsters in here.
The number of people who make a living
by stealing from others keeps growing.
Good people from this island
will leave if this continues.
That's why I can't forgive people like you.
Have mercy!
Kabru?
Hmm?
Oh, sorry about earlier.
It was the first solution I could think of.
Hmm.
What are you saying?
You know what?
Never mind.
Okay, if you say so.
I feel like we're messing up
and not actually making any progress.
You're right.
And this is the result of all of that.
It's really the worst.
You could stand to be a bit more encouraging.
There's no point in sugarcoating it.
This is just the best we can do for right now.
Huh.
The Island Lord only sees this dungeon
as a profitable tunnel.
If the gold runs dry,
he thinks that monster leather and bones
would be enough.
But no one's gonna dive into a dungeon
that's been thoroughly searched through.
Maybe because the get-rich-quick dream disappears,
or the spirit of adventure isn't being met.
The population starts to decline,
and then...
dangerous monsters pour out of the dungeon.
That's how a countless number of towns
have been destroyed.
We have to lift this place's curse and fast.
The world doesn't need monsters and dungeons.
Yeah.
I'm starving.
Being revived does make you hungry, huh?
Kabu!
Check it out!
Those guys were carrying
some pretty valuable things on them!
All right.
Let's only take their food,
and then sink the rest of it.
What? Why sink it?
If we take just everything,
it means we're no better than they are.
Once we're all finished,
how about we eat a little something?
Let's do it!
It's time for us to dig in!
Whoa!
Those guys were eating good!
I guess corpse retrievers get paid a lot.
Yeah, when you're making your own corpses
to take back.
And the Island Lord hasn't caught on to that?
There are actually inspections
when it comes to payments from the island.
But it seems like those guys
were getting around it.
It's honestly more likely
that there are a lot of people
working together behind the scenes.
Sounds like corruption.
They're digging their own graves
by doing that.
Should we try to report this?
I wouldn't expect the Island Lord
to come up with a good solution.
Only rookies like Donnie
would be affected by it.
If the Island Lord burst
after stuffing himself,
I wouldn't mind at all.
I'm pretty sure the Elves
would step in and take his place.
Yeah, so we still need him
to act as sort of a middleman.
We're dealing with a dwarf
and a tall man
and an elf and a half foot.
What are you muttering?
Those are the people in the party
that put the ghost warding spell on us.
Oh, the ones who stole our treasure.
The ones who stole our food.
There aren't very many parties
with an elf in them.
We might figure it out
if we narrow things down.
Maybe it's Donnie and Fiona?
It's hard to believe
that those two were able
to make it to the third floor.
Having only four party members is odd.
It's more reckless than anything.
Hey, Holm or Ren,
look closer at this ghost-repelling spell.
Wait, you still have that thing on?
Well, yeah, it's evidence.
That magic's not in my area of expertise.
Let me see.
Hmm.
Honor student.
It's like something
right out of a textbook.
The spell...
is pretty weak.
A magic school student, probably.
Everyone from there
all write spells in the same way.
I'm confident it was an elf specifically.
I see.
Is that so?
Wait.
Magic school student?
This all makes sense now.
Huh?
What does?
Oh, sorry.
I just realized something.
It's only a speculation.
But if I'm right,
it would make me really happy.
Come on, Kabru.
Stop beating around the bush.
All right.
Well,
this gotta be the Toten siblings party.
Those two, huh?
Really?
They didn't seem like the type
to want to do crime.
So why them?
First,
the younger sister of the duo
used to be a student
at a magic school.
Didn't an elf
put the ghost word on us, though?
And those siblings were tall men,
weren't they?
Whoa, I'm not done yet.
Just keep listening.
The elf and the younger sister
in that party
looked like they got along well.
It seemed like they were
maybe childhood friends or something.
I'm guessing that they were
at least classmates
at the same magic school.
It's rare here
for someone to be
from a magic school,
not to mention an elf.
Hmm.
It isn't that it's impossible.
But to only base it off that...
And besides,
Kuro said he only smelled
one tall man, didn't he?
Siblings would have had
two different scents.
Could that be the reason
they're recklessly exploring
with such a small party?
Exactly.
They lost either
the brother or the sister
and wanted to go save them.
But the party
had a dispute about it.
That's what I gathered,
considering we saw
one of them in a new party.
It seems like they've been
having disputes
about goals and income.
And because of this,
it's highly possible
that people left the group
at some point.
And that put them
in a bind.
So they took our stuff.
You're finally starting
to sound convincing.
Told you!
Wait.
Kuro said he also
smelled a dwarf.
Isn't that right, buddy?
I did.
Definitely did.
So isn't it weird
that they apparently
still have a dwarf with them?
They must have
a new dwarf tagging along.
Do we know exactly
who this party consists of?
Let's see.
The tall men
are Laios and Fallon.
And there's the eastern man
named Shiro.
The dwarf we saw earlier
is Namaari.
And the elf is Marcel.
I'm not positive,
but I think the half foot
is Chilchuk.
If it is the Toten party,
then that means Shiro,
Namaari,
and one of the siblings
aren't there anymore.
And the new dwarf
may have joined their ranks.
I see.
So that woman from earlier
was Namaari.
Huh.
Do you know anything,
Daya?
Only her name.
Since she's famous,
she's the child of someone
called Weapons Dealer.
What a name.
He's who dealt with all the weapon
and armor exchange
on this island.
One day,
he disappeared
after he was found
embezzling money.
It was that incident
that ruined the island lord's
image of us dwarves.
Ever since that happened,
a lot of us dwarves
faced hardships,
including myself.
I doubt any sane dwarf
would choose to take
her spot in a party.
Whoever it is
is insane, then.
Mikbel is right.
They smell dangerous.
I know a couple of details
about that Chilchuk guy, too.
He's delusional
in his old age
and seems to think
he's the representative
of the half-wits
on this island.
When he makes a contract
with someone,
he's like,
go through the guild
and pay me a broker's fee.
He's a great little bastard.
I'm not stupid enough
to join under terms
like that.
If the guild found out
I hired a kobold,
they'd definitely
say something to me.
You wouldn't want that.
You like working for me,
right, Kuro?
Mik feeds me.
He's the best boss
I could ask for.
I bet he's working
the poor thing
to the bone for peanuts.
You shouldn't say
things like that
just based on speculation.
Hey,
the Eastern Taman
is from the same place
as Rin, isn't he?
Does that mean
you know him?
Listen,
don't lump us together
because we're both Eastern.
Not all towns
speak the same language,
you know.
Besides,
the name Shuro
isn't even from my island.
Then let me share
what I know about him.
Even there,
he always managed
to stand out.
He came to the island
with some people
from his town
but decided to join
the Toten party.
It didn't seem like
he was a mere peasant
and wanted to use
the dungeon
to test his strength.
So he eventually
left the party, huh?
Don't think he'd be
concerned about money
or danger.
What if it was actually
both siblings
that left
and him who stayed?
No,
that's not right.
It's pretty creepy
how well you remember
things about people,
Kabru.
Why do you look
so excited?
Because I am excited.
This is so fun.
There are lots of people
on this island
and everyone acts
with completely
different motives.
But when all those
separate actions
eventually come together,
it becomes a historical moment
involving a large group.
I thought it was
a boring case of theft,
but I think things
are going to get
real interesting.
So I really hope
it's the Toten's party
because one of my
greatest wishes
is to be there
for the moment
when their mask
finally comes off.
You got some kind
of grudge against them?
They've done nothing
to me personally,
but in the past
they made quite a bit
of money from gold stripping.
But most of their earnings
were given to their party members
who were too injured
to explore.
Wow.
A happy ending?
It's a moving story,
if I didn't tell you
all the rest of it.
They weren't actually
still injured
and just pocketed
the money.
They never went back
to adventuring.
Now they sell
illegally manufactured
goods on the island.
I shall bestow
my kingdom
to whoever defeats
the mage.
Those were the words
of a man who claimed
to be king
of this country.
But whether or not
you're actually
given everything,
this dungeon itself
is a relic
left behind
long ago
by the ancient elves,
there's no doubt
you would gain
a great amount
of influence.
That's why
I really don't think
those siblings
should be the ones
to inherit it.
They don't seem
to care about that.
They're not leaders.
just like the island lord.
We completely get it,
Kabru.
We already know
you're the only one
fit to lead.
And he'll drive out
that stupid island lord,
too.
Well, if we're still
having trouble
with random monsters
in here,
we've clearly got
a long ways to go.
Yeah, you're right.
We should probably
start heading out now.
I hope that we can
return without
any more incidents.
Whoa, what the...
It's a bladefish.
Don't let the fish
distract you.
The real danger's
right under our...
A kraken?
No, a sea serpent.
Red, get away!
I can't...
Home!
I can't summon her
in a situation like this.
Weird stuff
could get mixed in.
Stay calm.
You've got to do
something, Kabru.
It's not moving
in a complicated way.
Discern these movements.
Find this carotid artery.
Where even is that artery?
Excuse me.
Tade!
Aye-yi!
My lord!
If you'd please!
That was simply
incredible.
Are there any stains
on your garment?
No.
You must be tired.
Shall we rest here
for a meal?
No.
We press on.
Our lord's being
quite bullheaded.
It's only because
he's head over heels
for that northern woman.
Tade's feeling
extremely hungry.
Are you hurt anywhere,
Kabru?
I've changed my mind.
Huh?
I think if we boil this,
it might be delicious.
Disgusting.
Excuse me.
I would like to thank you
for saving us.
We would have been goners.
I'm Kabru.
May I ask your names?
You may not.
We're just passing
through here.
Sorry for eavesdropping,
but I think you were
looking for a woman.
Do you have any info?
Just as I thought.
I was right about that.
You're in luck.
We may be able
to help you out
in your search
for Fallon Toten.
Kuro, cut it out.
I told you to stop
making that face
because it's scary.
What the heck's
gotten into you, huh?
And with that,
Kabru and his party
will be continuing
into the dungeon.
Back to the present
with Laios' group.
Two days after deciding
to return home,
we hit a dead end.
Another dead end?
I'm so hungry.
I'm tired.
So thirsty.
They are currently lost
and on the verge of death.